Joshua Jumbo

Product Designer

Lives in Nigeria

I am a product designer with over 2 years of practical job experience. I understand basic front-end code that helps me communicate better with developers.

My core strength is in ux or user experience design.

I also do user interface or UI designs pretty well to. Recently, I got certified in the udacity nanodegree for user experience design Portfolio: joshuajumbo.com

Email: jumbojoshua91@gmail.com

Linkedin:

https://linkedin.com/in/joshuajumb91

Instagram:

https://instagram.com/jumbo_joshua

Phone: +2347038604375

Core Skills

User Research
Design System
User Interface Design (UI)
User Experience Design (UX)
Prototyping
Microinteraction

Work Experience

DPhi.tech | UI/UX Designer

Aug 2020 - Present | Remote, Belgium

Market Growth

- Reshaped DPhi's brand to bolster community growth through several designs
- End-to-end design process: from creating a vision for exploration, to creating concepts and building pixel-perfect solutions for test and implementation
- · Worked closely with the UX lead to properly solve user needs before interpreting them in ui design

Helped Make DPhi Investment Ready

 Through ui design, helped launch the DPhi assessment platform which made us more confident to seek for investment

Malon Technologies | UI/UX Designer(freelance)

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021 | Hybrid, Lagos, Nigeria

Remodelled/Rebranded Malon

- As the sole designer, contributed to remodelling Malon from being a digital agency to a SAAS company through UI design.
- · Led the design decisions on customer-centric products and solved ux edge cases with stakeholders
- Contributed to designing 2 mobile applications which were both customer centric.

Malon Technologies | UI/UX Designer(freelance)

Jan 2020 - May 2020 | Hybrid, Lagos, Nigeria

same as above

Amplify.ng | Junior UI/UX Designer (intern)

Apr 2019 - Aug 2019 | onsite, Lagos, Nigeria

· Contributed to social media brands that projected Amplify as a design-centric digital agency.

Softcity Group | Junior UI/UX Designer

Nov 2018 - Mar 2018 | onsite, Lagos, Nigeria

Contributed to modifying the designs that existed prior to when I joined

• I wore many hats for Softcity, firstly, I contributed to reducing the time from development to delivery by creating wireframes, sketches and low and high fidelity designs. Secondly, I contributed to increasing better hiring during my freetimes by assisting in HR duties and also interfaced with customers on the phone.

Microsoft4Afrika | Big Data Enginer(Graduate Trainee)

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018 | onsite, Lagos, Nigeria

· Contributed to cleaning and visualizing data as dashboards and reports using power-bi, R and Azure

Education

University of Uyo | 4.0 of 5.0 | Second Class Upper

Apr 2012 - Apr 2017 | B.Eng In Computer Engineering

- Graduated as part of the best in my department
- Led my department as the president

Non-Product Design Highlights

Hackathon Winner | Neri Hackathon for Change Initiative

Jul 2019 | First Place

 Competed in a 3-day hackathon sprint on how to better impact people vulnerable to terrorism and came up with a solution that helped my team win the grand price

Certifications

Udacity Nanodegree In User Experience Design

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021 | Awarded by Udacity

MCP in Big Data Engr.

July 2018 | Awarded by Microsoft